Guide to the Alexander Jackson Davis Architectural Drawing Collection 1827-1884 PR 16
New-York Historical Society
- Geographical Society "Principle for Collocating Books Uniting Economy - Light - Access - Classsification" ink, graphite UM (Item 062 recto)
- Georgraphical Society Library "GEOG. SOC. LIB." ink, graphite UR (Item 064a recto)
- Gothic ruins [Perspective of Gothic Ruins]
- Gothic ruins drawing (Item [604])
- Gothic ruins, study of a castle (Item 554 recto)
- Gothic ruins, study of a castle (Item 554 recto)
- Gothic villa or cottage, unidentified (Item 158c)
- Gothic villa, unidentified (Item 158a)
- Gothic villa, unidentified (Item 158b)
- Grace Church (Item 510)
- Green, Charles Cottage "U.S.N. Lt Charles Green, Windsor CT 1845 Plan for a Cottage in 1845" ink, graphite BR (Item 279)
  Windsor (Conn.)
- Green, William E. House "EAST." ink wash LC (Item 104b recto)
  see also drawing #104a
- Green, William E. House "WEST" ink LC (Item 104b verso)
  see also drawing #103a
- Green, William E. Residence (Item 104a)
- Harral, H. K. House, Walnut Wood "Working Drawing No. 3 Plan of Drawing-room ceiling 1/2 inch to foot" ink, graphite UL "Ceiling of Room over drawing-rm" ink, graphite UR "Per (Item 259)
  Bridgeport (Conn.)
  Deomolished 1958
- Harvey House "Harvey. Philadelphia Cellar. 1 Basement 2." (Item 93)
  Philadelphia (Penn.)
- Harvey House "Harvey. Philadelphia Principal no.3 Second no. 4" (Item 92)
- Haskell, Llewellyn S. House, Eyrie "Eagle Rock, N. J." NA ML (Item 275n.29)
  West Orange (N.J.)
  bound with "Rural Residences"; remodeling of farmhouse (1853-54, add.1856), observatory tower, demolished 1920s, Peck, Alexander J. Davis, 115
- Haskell, Llewellyn S. House, Eyrie "EYRIE." ink MC (Item [613])
  Orange Mountain, West Orange; remodeling of farmhouse (add. 1856) and observatory tower (1853-56), demolished 1920s,Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis,115
- Haskell, Llewellyn S. Investment house (Item 114a)
  West Bloomfield (N.J.)
  see projects for Haskell investment houses in West Bloomfield in Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 117-118; see also darwings #114 b, c, d
- Haskell, Llewellyn S. Investment house (Item 114b)
  see projects for Haskell investment houses in Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 117-118;elevation hardly visible; see also drawings # 114 a, c, d
- Haskell, Llewellyn S. Investment house (Item 114)
  see projects for investment house for Haskell in West Bloomfield (now Montclair) in Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 117-118; see also #114 a, b, c
- Haskell, Llewellyn S. Investment house (Item 114c)
  see projects for Haskell investment houses in West Bloomfield in Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 117-118; see also drawings #114 a, b, d
- Heiss, John P. House "Copy of plan for John P. Heiss, Esq. Washington, D.C." (Item 91)
  Washington (D.C.)
- Hemingway, A. G. House "For painting the Ceiling" ink graphite BR (Item 281)
  part of a set of villas and cottages for Richard Lathers and his friends.
- Herrick, John J. House, Ericstan; chimney study (Item 555)
  Tarrytown (N.Y.)
  furniture design for Ericstan; house demolished 1944; some furniture extant, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 116
- Higgins, George Block of Houses, Houses of Mansions "WEST."ink, UC (Item 436)
  11 houses unified in one design, Gothic Revival, northern part became Rutgers Female seminary, demolished, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 117
- Hillhouse, James A. House, Highwood (Item 289)
  1829-1831, house, ice house, children's playhouse (1835), farmerhouse (1839, Gothic cottage), demolished 1943, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 105
- Historical Society "Basement." (Item 050 verso)
- Historical Society (Item 050 recto)
- Historical Society "Library and Aud" (Item 044 recto)
  watermark "JWhatman 1868"
- Historical Society (Item 044 verso)
- Historical Society "Historical society." ink UL (Item 592)
- Historical Society (Item 048 verso)
- Historical Society - library "Historical Society" (Item 46)
- Hoadley, David residence "Hoadley Study/tower S. end. No 1." graphite UR (Item 069a)
  remodeling of I. Smith and Shepard Homans House and coach house/stable (1859-1861), Pack, Alexander Jackson Davis, 118; see also drawings #069-080
- Hoadley, David residence "Hoadley Study WEST END" graphite LL (Item 069b)
- Hoadley, David residence "Details wanted. House of D. Hoadley. Esq." ink UL-UR (Item 069g recto)
  request by Davis, answer by Hoadley (see 069f); remodeling of Homans house (1859-1861), Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 118; see also drawings #69-80
- Hoadley, David residence "Measured by A. J. Davis. (Item 069g verso)
- Hoadley, David residence "Cellar & Foundations. Drawing No. 1." ink UL (Item 70)
  remodeling of Homans House (1859-1861), demolished, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 118; see also drawings #069-080
- Hoadley, David residence "Principal floor. 2." ink UL (Item 71)
- Hoadley, David residence "Second Floor. 3." ink UL-UC (Item 72)
- Hoadley, David residence "No. 4. Tower room & attic: roof-gables & valleys." ink UL-UC (Item 73)
- Hoadley, David residence "NORTH. No. V." ink LC (Item 74)
- Hoadley, David residence "SOUTH. No. VI. REAR." ink LC (Item 75)
- Hoadley, David residence "WEST END." ink LC (Item 076a)
- Hoadley, David residence "WEST. No. VII." ink LC (Item 076b)
- Hoadley, David residence "Section. No. 8." ink, ink wash UR (Item 77)
- Hoadley, David Residence, letter to A. J. Davis from David Hoadley (Item 69)
  see informations on 069g recto; remodeling of Homans house (1859-1861), Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 118; see also drawings #069-080
- Homans, I. Smith and Shepard residence "Homans. No 2.7 Study" graphite UR (Item 78)
  see Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 118 and drawings #069-080; drawn on an erased sketch
- Homans, I. Smith and Shepard residence "WEST END." ink MC; "Principal floor" ink MR (Item 79)
  see Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 118 and drawings #069-080
- Homans, I. Smith and Shepard residence "HOMANS REAR SOUTH" ink wash LC (Item 80)
- Hospital "Longitudinal Section" (Item 31)
- Hospital (Item 33)
- Hospital "Transverse Sections" "Section thro' the corridor." "Section thro' the large rooms." (Item 031e)
- Hospital (Item 031b-c)
  see 31a
- Hospital [Hospital for the Insane] "Design for a Hospital" ink CL (Item 031a)
  "and spacious Halls are not essential parts of this design." BR ink, graphite. thumbnail plan BL; hinged as if in book. see 31b-c. Newton p. 130.
- Hotel "Principal Floor for a Hotel. 2." graphite LL (Item 333)
- Hotel Constitution Island "Upper Floors" (Item 034 c)
  Constitution Island (N.Y.)
  for Henry W. Warner, not executed
- Hotel Constitution Island (Item 034 b)
  shows floor plan and site, for Henry W. Warner, not executed
- Hotel Constitution Island "Study for Hotel, Constitution Island" (Item 034 a)
- Hotel Constitution island (Item 37)
  Design for a hotel for Henry W. Warner. Not executed. Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 109.
- Hotel Constitution Island "SOUTH FRONT" ink LL (Item 36)
  hotel for W. Warner, not executed, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 109
- Hotel for Union Square or three houses "Hotel for Union Sq. or Three Houses" ink, graphite BL (Item 247b)
- House based on Baughman and John Munn houses "Study on Baughman and John Munn" (Item 95)
  Baughman demolished. Munn extant, now Dowling Nursing Home, veranda partially enclosed, some interior changes
- House or villa, unidentified "Plan of Principal Story." ink LC (Item 413 recto)
- House or villa, unidentified (Item 413 verso)
- House or villa, unidentified "3. Second story." ink UC (Item 414)
- House or villa, unidentified "Basement. No.1." ink UL; "Principal. No.2." ink UR (Item 416)
- House or villa, unidentified (Item 415)
  maybe project for George Ellwanger Villa, 1858; see Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 117 and drawing #124
- House, Gothic, unidentified "Study on Viesi." graphite UR (Item 529)
  see also drawing #530
- House, Gothic, unidentified (Item 530)
  see also drawing #529
- House, Palladian style, unidentified "PALLADIAN." ink LC (Item 437)
- House, six-story, unidentified "SECOND FLOOR" ink wash, ink LC (Item 477)
  see also drawing #476
- House, six-story, unidentified "BASEMENT" ink wash LC (Item 476)
  see also drawing #477
- House, square two-story, unidentified (Item 563 verso)
  see also recto; secondary support is primary support of another drawing
- House, square two-story, unidentified "B" graphite UR; "East end." ink LC; "Section from East to West." ink MC (Item 563 recto)
  see also verso; secondary support is also primary support of a drawing
- House, suburban "Suburban" graphite UR (Item 165)
  see also #164 recto-verso
- House, three-story, unidentified "PRINCIPAL FLOOR No. 2" ink, ink wash LL (Item 475)
- House, two-story, unidentified (Item 478)
- House, unidentified (Item 106)
- House, unidentified (Item 420 verso)
- House, unidentified (Item 419)
- House, unidentified "2 Story" graphite UR (Item 434)
- House, unidentified (Item 180(2))
  see also drawing #180(1)
- House, unidentified "Transverse Section. No.9" ink, graphite UR. "Principal story. No.2" (Item 246e-f)
  primary support is two sheets of tan and grey/green paper glued together.
- House, unidentified "Elevation west end. No.7" ink, graphite UR, "Attic and roof, No.4" ink, graphite CR (Item 246g-h)
  primary support is two sheets of paper glued together.
- House, unidentified (Item 246i)
- House, unidentified (Item 480)
- House, unidentified (Item 479)
- House, unidentified "Single house" graphite UR (Item 435)
- House, unidentified (Item 433)
- House, unidentified "Plan for central high gable and two story towers." ink LR; "No. 4 attic." graphite UR; "Two rooms, with closets, in the roof." ink UC (Item 549)
- House, unidentified "Basement 1." graphite UR (Item 553)
  see also drawing #552 (principal floor) and 567
- House, unidentified "Study for a house extended in length." ink UL; "Principal 2" ink, graphite UR (Item 552)
  see also drawings #553 (basement) and 567
- House, unidentified (Item 558)
  a lift-up over doors shows variations in door treatment
- House, unidentified (Item 576)
- House, unidentified "SUBURBAN." ink ML (Item 161)
- House, unidentified (Item 418)
- House, unidentified (Item 420 recto)
- House, unidentified (Item 421)
- House, unidentified "Dorian" graphite UR (Item 422)
- House, unidentified (Item 425)
  see also drawing #424
- House, unidentified (Item 424)
  see also drawing #425
- House, unidentified (Item 403)
  see also drawing #404
- House, unidentified (Item 404)
  see also drawing #403
- House, unidentified (Item 400)
- House, unidentified (Item 406)
  drawn on verso of a letter
- House, unidentified "Additions to house. N. E." graphite UR (Item 387)
- House, unidentified (Item 388)
  see also drawing #399
- House, unidentified "NORTH END. 6." ink MC (Item 399)
  see also drawing #388
- House, unidentified (Item 171)
  sketch of a plan on verso
- House, unidentified (Item 173 verso)
- House, unidentified "Second story." ink UR (Item 173 recto)
- House, unidentified (Item 177 recto)
- House, unidentified (Item 177 verso)
- House, unidentified "PLANS.. SHEWING VARIOUS METHODS FOR ARRANGING THE STAIRS." watercolor, ink UL-UR (Item 180(1))
  see also drawing #180(2)
- House, unidentified "Elevation of the East side. No. 6." ink LL-LR (Item 535)
- House, unidentified (Item 536)
  some architectural similarities with Merrick House (see drawing #83a)
- House, unidentified "Masons estimate for 5 houses" graphite UL-UC (Item 501)
  could be related to J. V. C. Smith town house (drawing #285)
- House, unidentified (Item 248)
  Augusta (Me.)
- House, unidentified (Item 568)
- House, unidentified "Masons estimate for 5 houses" graphite UL-UC (Item 501)
- House, unidentified [G. W. Penny?] "Cellar plan. No. 1." (Item 246a)
- House, unidentified [G. W. Penny?] "Section on line A-B C-D. No. 8" ink, graphite UR "Plan of Second Story. 3." ink, graphite CR (Item 246c-d)
  primary support is two sheets of paper glued together
- House, unidentified, "Highland Villa" verso, graphite LL "Highland Villa" verso, graphite LL; "Second story.3." ink UR (Item 412)
- House, unidentified, [Baum House?] (Item 149 recto)
  see also verso and drawings #148 recto-verso
- House, unidentified, [Baum House?] (Item 149 verso)
  see also recto and drawings #148 recto-verso
- Howland, Gardnor G. House "Design A. G. Howland" ink, graphite CR (Item 282b)
  Flushing (New York, N.Y.)
- Howland, Gardnor G. House "Design B. 1834. First study for a country dwelling near Flsihing for Gardnor Howland" ink, graphite CL-CR (Item 282 verso)
- Howland, Gardnor G. House "Design A Second floor first study for Gardnor G. Howland near Flishing L. I. 1834" ink, graphite UR (Item 282 recto)
  extensively reworked later on
- Hull, Amos G. House "AMOS G. HULL. M.D. NORMAN VILLA. NEWBURG." ink LL-LR; "NORTH." ink wash LL; "SOUTH." ink wash LR (Item 272a)
  not executed; gatehouse (see #103), gate and watch turret executed, demolished in 1960s, extant, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 114; see also #272b
- Hull, Amos G. House "Opera. A. AMOS G. HULL. M. D. NEWBURGH HILL." ink UR (Item 272b recto)
  not executed; gatehouse (see #103), gate and watch turret executed, demolished in 1960s, extant, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 114; see also #272a
- Hull, Amos G. House (Item 272b verso)
- Huntington, Edward House "First Plan for Ed. Huntington Esq. Rome N.Y." ink BL (Item 280)
  Rome (N.Y.)
  Demolished.
- Huntington, Edward House "Suburban" watercolor, graphite BM (Item 258)
  1845 addition, demolished
- Iselin House (Item 107a)
  see also drawings #107b, 108a-b
- Iselin House (Item 107b)
  see also drawings #107a, 108a-b
- Iselin House "OLD FRENCH" graphite LC (Item 108a)
  see also drawings #107a-b, 108b
- Iselin House "Second Story. Iselin." ink UR (Item 108b)
  see also drawings #107a-b, 108a
- Janin House "Attic." ink UC (Item 128)
  unidentified; see also drawings #126-127
- Janin House "Principal." ink UC (Item 127)
  unidentified; see also drawings #126-128; drawing #126 on same drawing paper
- Janin House "Basement." ink UC (Item 126)
  unidentified; see also drawings #127-128; drawing #127 on same drawing paper
- Jefferson Market "Jefferson Market and Courthouse (Item 021 b)
- Jefferson Market "Offices Jefferson Market" (Item 021a recto)
- Jefferson Market "Offices Jefferson Market" (Item 021a verso)
- Jefferson Market "Jefferson Market and Courthouse (Item 021 b)
- Johnson, R. C. House "Principal Floor, Plan of a dwelling-house designed for Mr. R. C. Johson Oswego N.Y. A copy Alex. J. Davis Arc't." (Item 98)
  Oswego (N.Y.)
- Jones Court "Jones, Wall - St." (Item 012b)
- Lathers, Richard House, [Winyah?] "FRENCH CHATEAU." watercolor LC (Item 125)
  for Winah, see Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 114-115 and drawing #275n.27
- Lathers, Richard Residence, Winyah "WINYAH. THE RESIDENCE OF. COL. RICHARD LATHERS, NEW ROCHELLE, N.Y. A. J. Davis, Architect." NA MC (Item 275n.27)
  bound with "Rural Residences"; house (1851-52, addition 1856-57), coach house (1863), demolished, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 115; see #125
- Law, Dr. House "First Floor Second Floor" ink, graphite BL-BR (Item 283)
- Lenox Library (Item 003 verso)
  see 003recto; see also #0 - 10 for related projects. JWhatman 1868 watermark
- Lenox Library "Lenox E.3" UR ink (Item 5)
  see also drawings #0-10
- Lenox Library "East Front For The Lenox Library" (Item 003 recto)
  see also drawings #0-10, wm: JWhatman 1868
- Lenox Library "For a Public Library" ink, CL (Item 001a)
  see also #0 - 10 for related projects.
- Library "Grammatical Design for a Library Sounds - Signs - Words - Letters - For And By The Whole People" watercolor, ink, graphite BL - BR (Item 8)
  see also related library drawings #0 - 10.
- Library "For a Library With or Without a Portico" (Item 2)
  See also other library drawings particularly: #s 1 -10
- Library (Item 7)
  Elevation done on separate sheet collaged to recto measures: 13 5/16" x 17 6/16". See also other library drawings particularly: #s 1 -10
- Library (Item 000 recto)
- Library "Insulated Library Building with an Audience Hall Below" ink, graphite UL-UR (Item 065 verso)
  see 65 recto
- Library "Design for a Great Library 100 or 200 FT Diameter" watercolor and graphite UL-UR (Item 009 verso)
  see also #0-10.
- Library "Library with Alcoves for books in Rotunda Reading Room" watercolor, ink, graphite UL-UR (Item 065 recto)
  pricked guide marks, see 65 verso
- Library and auditorium "Library and Aduitorium." ink, graphite BL - BR (Item 006 recto)
  see also related library drawings #0 - 10. wm: "JWhatman 1868"
- Library and lecture hall (Item 001b)
- Library Palmyrean style "Palmyrean" (Item 305)
- Library with alcoves in a rotunda "Library with Alcoves in a Rotunda" ink LC (Item 304 verso)
- Library, Monumental "Monumental Design for a Library" watercolor, BL-BR (Item 009 recto)
- Library, unidentified "Library" (Item 11)
- Library, unidentified (Item 304 recto)
- Library, unidentified "2D FLOOR LIBRARY" ink, graphite MC (Item 594 verso)
- Library, unidentified (Item 594 recto)
  the two rooms in this plan are State Library and Court Law Library
- Lindsey, Jesse, Esq. House "Principal Story 13 fl: 23 rises for Jesse Lindsey, Esq. Greensboro. N.C. Jan. 1853" (Item 99)
  Greensboro (N.C.)
  For remodelling of house, not executed.
- Litchfield Edward H. Residence (Item 374b)
  not executed, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 119
- Litchfield, E. C. House "Section" watercolor, ink, graphite UL, "Rear" watercolor, ink, graphite UR (Item 275a)
  partial graphite section, elevation on verso. designs for Edwin Clark Litchfield for his properties in brooklyn, various styles, execution unknown
- Litchfield, E. C. House "E. C. Litchfield" ink, graphite UM (Item 275e)
- Litchfield, E. C. House "Second floor. 4" ink, graphite UR (Item 275)
- Litchfield, E. C. House (Item 275h)
- Litchfield, E. C. House "No. 6 Litchfield Rear No. 7" (Item 275k)
- Litchfield, E. C. House (Item 275m)
- Litchfield, E. C. House (Item 275l)
  wm: JWhatman 1868. Designs for Edwin Clark Litchfield for his properties in Brooklyn, various styles, execution unknown
- Litchfield, E. C. House (Item 275j)
- Litchfield, E. C. House "Section. Cellar, Basement. Principal. Second. Attic. Elevation" graphite, ink, UL-UR (Item 275b)
  design for Edwin Clark Litchfield for his properties in Brooklyn, various styles, execution unknown
- Litchfield, E. C. House "Front - Rear" watercolor, BL-BR (Item 275)
  designs for Edwin Clark Litchfield for his properties in Brooklyn, various style, execution unknown
- Litchfield, E. C. Villa "Principal floor No. 2." ink, graphite UR (Item 275i)
- Litchfield, Edward H. Residence (Item 374a)
- Litchfield, Edward H. Residence (Item 374b)
- Litchfield, Edwin Clark Villa, Grace Hill "SPECIFICATION OF THE MATERIALS AND WORKS REQUIRED FOR BUILDING A DWELLING HOUSE on long island. [Brooklyn, 9 & 10 av. 3 to 5th. FOR Mrs. Edwi (Item 275n.2)
  volume of specifications (8 pages recto-verso) bound with pages from "Rural residences" (see also 275n.3-14); See Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 116
- Litchfield, Edwin Clark Villa, Grace Hill (Item 275n.3)
  volume of specifications and drawings bound with pages from "Rural residences" (see also 275n.2-14); See Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 116
- Litchfield, Edwin Clark Villa, Grace Hill "Plan of Principal floor." ink LC (Item 275n.5)
- Litchfield, Edwin Clark Villa, Grace Hill "NORTH." ink MC; "SOUTH" ink LC (Item 275n.6)
- Litchfield, Edwin Clark Villa, Grace Hill "EAST." ink MC; "SECTION SOUTH TO NORTH." ink LC (Item 275n.7)
- Litchfield, Edwin Clark Villa, Grace Hill "Finish of Drawing room." ink UL; "Finish of Parlor: Oak." ink UR; "Finish of Dining room" ink MR (Item 275n.8)
- Litchfield, Edwin Clark Villa, Grace Hill "Hall ceiling." ink LR (Item 275n.9)
  volume of specifications and drawings bound with pages from "Rural Residences" (drawings #275n.2-14); see also Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 116
- Litchfield, Edwin Clark Villa, Grace Hill (Item 275n.10)
- Litchfield, Edwin Clark Villa, Grace Hill "Sash of Windows in library, and in the second story, over parlor, drawingroom, dining room, and others." ink LL-LR (Item 275n.11)
- Litchfield, Edwin Clark Villa, Grace Hill (Item 275n.12)
  volume of specifications and drawings bound with pages from "Rural Residences" (see #275n.2-14); see also Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 116
- Litchfield, Edwin Clark Villa, Grace Hill (Item 275n.13)
- Litchfield, Edwin Clark Villa, Grace Hill "Basement plan. No. 1." ink LL; "Second story." ink ML (Item 275n.4)
  volume of specifications and drawings bound with pages from "Rural Residences" (see also 275n.2-14); See Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 116
- Litchfield, Edwin Clark Villa, Grace Hill, Coach House and Stable (Item 275n.14 verso)
- Litchfield, Edwin Clark Villa, Grace Hill, Coach House and Stable "Coach House & Stable for Rigdewood L.J." ink LL (Item 275n.14 recto)
- Log church to accommodate 400 persons (Item 195)
  plate from book?
- Log church, unidentified "PLAN OF A LOG CHURCH TO ACCOMODATE 400 PERSONS." NA LL; "Ground plan." NA ML; "Side elevation." NA UL; "End elevation." NA UR; "Section of th (Item 500)
  page from illustrated book?
- Long Island Historical Society "PLAN FOR THE LONG ISL. HISTORICAL SOC. LIB. BROOKLYN." ink LL-LR (Item 053 recto)
  competition, not executed, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis; see also drawings #052, 55-59
- Long Island Historical Society "STUDY FOR L.I. HIST. SOC. LIB." ink MC (Item 055 recto)
  competition, not executed, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 119; study inspired by one for the NY Historical Society (1870); see also #052-059
- Long Island Historical Society "FOR THE LONG ISLAND HIST. SOC." ink UC (Item 56)
  competition, not executed, Peck, Alexander Jackson davis, 119; see also drawings #052, 053, 055, 057-059
- Long Island Historical Society "SECTION LOOKING WEST" ink MC; "SECTION LOOKING EST." ink LC (Item 057 recto)
  competition, not executed, Peck, Alexander Jacskon Davis, 119; see also verso and drawings # 052, 053, 055, 056, 058, 059
- Long Island Historical Society (Item 58)
  competition, not executed, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 119; see also drawings #052, 053, 055, 056, 057, 059
- Long Island Historical Society "Design for the Long Island Historical Soc. AUDIENCE HALL" ink UR-MR; "Library for the L. I. Historical Soc. LIBRARY OVER AUD. HALL." ink MR-L (Item 59)
  competition, not executed, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 119; see also drawings #052, 053, 055-058; drawn on verso of a petition
- Long Island Historical Society (Item 057 verso)
  competition, not executed, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 119; see also recto and drawings #052, 053, 055, 056, 058, 059
- Long Island Historical Society "STUDY FOR L. I. HISTORICAL SOC." ink wash LC (Item 52)
  competition, not executed, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 119; see also drawings #053 recto, 55-59
- Lyceum of Natural History (Item 022b)
  Built version different, published p. 17 "A.J. Davis and American Classicism" 1989 catalogue for Federal Hall Exhibition. Demolished.
- Lyndhurst; Merritt, George House "List of Corbels for Knoll." ink, UR (Item 377 recto)
  remodeling of Knoll, extant, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 118
- Lyndhurst; Merritt, George House "Things to do." ink, UL; "Arch spandrels Billiard rm" graphite MR (Item 377 verso)
  remodeling of Knoll, extant, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 118; drawn on "TARIFF OF PRICES FOR AMERICAN AND FRENCH WINDOW GLASS."
- Lyon, Samuel E. Cottage "SECOND FLOOR." watercolor LR (Item 132 recto)
  later moved to 7 Lyon Place, rear addition 1847; gardener's house 1851; demolished 1948, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 110; see also #133, 150
- Lyon, Samuel E. Cottage "HOUSE 35 FT SQUARE, ADMITTING OF ADDITIONS." watercolor UR (Item 132 verso)
- Lyon, Samuel E. Cottage (Item 133 verso)